Privacy Policy
==============

Niche.com, Inc. (“Niche”, “we”, “us”, or “ours”) is committed to protecting your privacy. We have prepared this Privacy Policy and Notice (“Policy”) to describe our practices regarding our collection and use of the personal information of individuals who interact with our mobile apps or website (collectively referred to as our “Site”) and to inform you of your rights with respect to our data collection practices. This Policy provides information about the types of information that we collect, and what we may do with that information. It also describes with whom we share it, and how we keep it secure.

In this Policy, we will outline and describe the following with respect to the personal information that we collect:

* Categories of information we collect and its sources
* How we use your information – our purpose for collection 
* With whom we share your information
* Opt-out – your choices
* Cross-border transfers of information
* How long we keep your information, your right to delete it and correct it
* Security of your information
* Liability limits
* Questions and contact information
* Children
* Notice to California residents – your California privacy rights
* Nevada privacy rights
* Effective date of this Privacy Policy and changes

The services that we provide and to which this Policy applies include online services such as email newsletters, online content including relevant targeted ads, scholarship listings, and mobile applications for various medium or devices in use now or in the future (together, the “Services”). 

**I.** **Categories of Information we collect and its sources**

**A.** **_Information you provide_****:**

If you create a login account on our Site, the personal information that you provide includes your name and email address, and such other information as we may require. Also, if you contact us, we collect additional information such as your location, and any personal information that you provide in your contact request. We also collect your personal data when you call us on our service number. This includes information, such as your name and contact information, your phone number as well as the content of your message.

We also collect other information in the form of the content that you choose to submit during your use of our Site. For example, if you apply for or win a scholarship contest, you may be asked for information, such as high school graduation year, that Niche may share with schools for which you have expressed interest. Other information that you may choose to submit when using the Services or our Site includes your age, citizenship, details of academic and work history, work place, preferences and goals related to the Niche Services, test scores and other personally sensitive information entered into your user account. Likewise, if you post in a user review or opinion survey, or comment on one of our articles our blogs, the information that you post becomes public, and is a part of the information about you that we collect. This information may include your personal comments and positions on topics which could include political information and other information of a sensitive nature that you choose to submit.

**B.** **_Information collected automatically_****:** 

Whether or not you create an account with us, certain information that identifies you may be passively collected and stored on our or our service providers’ server logs, including your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, operating system and information regarding what pages you accessed when you visited our Site, and when (e.g., the date and time of your visit to our Site), and the information for which you searched and which you viewed. 

We also use “Cookies”, “pixel tags” and other tracking technologies to make our online services more useful to you and to tailor the experience with us to meet your special interests and needs. For information about Cookies, pixel tags and other tracking technologies used on our Site, please see our separate [Cookie Policy](https://www.niche.com/about/cookie-policy/). If you choose to disable Cookies, some aspects of our Services may perform differently, for instance, you will need to re-enter your information each time you return to use the Services.

**C.** **_Information collected from third parties_****:** 

We may also collect information about you from any social network or other platform (such as from Facebook, Twitter or other third-party social network sites) that you may have connected to or from. This information includes your login and profile information, and the actual social media networks you used. Further, we may associate this personal information obtained from these sources with the other personal information we have collected about you from other sources as described in this Policy. We do not control or supervise how these third-party sources process your personal information, and any request that you have regarding the disclosure of your personal information from them to us should be made directly to those third parties (such as Facebook).

In addition to the information that we collect as described above, we also collect information about you from our third-party integrators and vendors, such as Google Analytics, Fullstory, and similar services. Personal data that we collect through these channels includes for example, IP address, access times, browser type and language, device type, device identifiers.

**II.** **How we use your information – our purpose for collection** 

For each of the categories of personal information set forth in Section I above, we use your personal information in order to provide you with meaningful and relevant Services, which includes information about schools, where to live and where to work. In addition, we may use your personal information for the following purposes:

* to respond to any questions or comments that you submitted to us on our Site or otherwise;
* to carry out any obligations entered into between us, such as providing you with Services that you have requested;
* to notify you of changes to our Services;
* to seek your views or comments on the Services we provide and send you communications by post, e-mail or text message which you have requested or that may be of interest to you, including newsletters, or promotions of our Services or events;
* to measure the adequate performance of our interactions with you;
* to obtain or maintain insurance coverage, manage risks or obtain professional advice and defend our rights and establish, exercise and defend our legal claims; 
* to facilitate your use of your web account on the Site; or
* to otherwise provide, create and maintain a trusted online environment and comply with our legal obligations.

In using your personal information, we may share some or all of it with authorized representatives of schools, work-places, and other entities that you may designate whose services relate to the Niche Services. Please refer to Section III of this Policy below for a full description of our information sharing practices.

**III.** **With whom we share your information**

**A.**  **_Per your instruction or use of the Services/Consents:_**

We may share all categories of your personal information to selected outside companies, either by selling it or otherwise transferring it, to advertisers and other business partners that assist us in providing you with meaningful and relevant Services (each, collectively an “Advertiser”). Our Advertisers include realtors, loan providers and other complementary service companies, schools, work places, and social media platforms such as Facebook. The sharing of your personal information with these Advertisers is conducted in accordance with the contact preferences that you set when you create your user profile, or when you express an interest in any content displayed on our Site, or when you enter a response to any affirmative authorization that you provide by typing it in a space provided or clicking on an icon designed to show your interest in an item on the web page or in the app. 

In addition, any personal information you share publicly through our Site may be indexed through third party search engines, such as Google or Bing. We do not control the practices of third-party search engines, and they may use caches containing your information, including any outdated information. You acknowledge that personal information that you submit when you participate in an opinion survey or user review, a blog or any online message board that we provide through our Site or Services may be available, via the Internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the disclosure to or use (or misuse) of such personal information by others, nor can we ensure it is deleted if you later ask us to delete your personal information as provided for in this Policy. 

**B.** **_Third party processors:_**

We also share your personal information with third party processors who act on our behalf (including contractors and service providers) to provide our web and app services and to help with our operations on our behalf (“Processors”). These Processors need access to and use of your personal information, and include third parties to provide us with technical support, to give us additional personal data about you, and to perform analytics and other work that we may need to outsource. These Processors are bound by law and/or contract to protect the confidentiality and security of your personal information.  They only process your personal information to provide requested services for us, and only act on our documented instructions. In addition, we use certain third-party Processors, such as Google’s reCAPTCHA service, to validate login credentials of individuals and to frustrate bots; in these cases, your privacy rights are determined by the Processor’s privacy policy.

We also share all categories of your personal information with other business partners that perform certain functions for us (“Business Partners”).  These Business Partners are themselves responsible to determine the purposes and/or means of the processing your personal information and for the lawfulness of that processing.  They include insurance companies, financial institutions, and other professional advisors.

**C.** **_Third party websites_****:**

We provide links to other websites, such as social networking sites (e.g., Facebook, Twitter and Google), or our third-party partner websites (such as scholarship providers, schools, and Business Partners), and these other websites may provide links to our Site. Third party sites operate according to their own terms of use and privacy policies and Niche has no control over these third-party websites. **_If you wish to opt-out of any information sharing conducted by any third-party website that you link to from us, or to us from them, you must do so in accordance with their specific opt-out policies and procedures._** **_By using our Site and Services, you acknowledge and agree that we are not responsible for the availability of such third-party sites, and do not endorse and are not responsible or liable for any content, advertising, products or other materials on or available from such sites. You further acknowledge and agree that Niche will not be responsible or liable, directly or indirectly, for any damage or loss caused or alleged to be caused by or in connection with use of or reliance on any content, advertising, products, or other materials on or available from such sites._** 

**D.** **_De-identified information about you_****:**

We also share aggregated or de-identified information (i.e., information that does not personally identify you directly), or statistical information about you, including statistical data and historical use data, with others for a variety of purposes, including for their own uses, for example, for improving their services for you and others. 

**E.** **_As required by law or legitimate business interest_****:** 

In addition, we may disclose any or all categories of your personal information where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. Likewise, we may disclose all such categories of your personal information to our professional advisers as is reasonably necessary for the purposes of managing risks, obtaining professional advice, or the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. Further, we may share some or all of your personal information in connection with or during negotiation of any merger or similar transaction involving sale or transfer of some or all of our business or assets. If another company acquires our company or assets, that company will possess the personal information collected by us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.

**IV.** **Opt-Out – your choices**

You have the right to request that we do not sell your personal information to Advertisers. 

IF YOU LIVE IN CALIFORNIA – When you first come to our Site, you will be given the option to click on a “Do Not Sell My Information” button on our landing page. If you click this button, we will not sell your identifiable personal information to Advertisers. We may still sell de-identified information about you, but the Advertisers will not be able to trace this information back to you or use it to market their products and services specifically to you. To opt-out, you may submit your request through our webform by clicking [here](https://preferences.niche.com/dont_sell), or submit a general privacy request in compliance with CCPA by clicking [here](https://preferences.niche.com/privacy); or you may send us an email to privacy@niche.com, putting the words “remove my name” in the subject line of your email and a request to opt-out in the body of the email, and our support team will guide you through the process of opting out. 

NO MATTER WHERE YOU LIVE – If you do not initially opt-out or at some point after giving us your personally identifiable information you later decide to limit the sale of your information to our third party Advertisers, or you no longer desire to continue to receive additional information from us about Niche and our Advertisers, you may “opt out” by submitting your request through our webform by clicking [here](https://www.niche.com/contact/), or by emailing us at privacy@niche.com, putting the words “remove my name” in the subject line of your email and a request to opt-out in the body of the email, and our support team will guide you through the process of opting out. Please note however that an Advertiser may have saved a copy of your account and account-related information from before you opted out. In the case of our email newsletters, you may opt out by clicking on the “opt out” link at the end of each email. If you agree to receive autodialed or pre-recorded calls and/or text messages from an Advertiser and later wish to opt-out, you should follow the direction in such call(s) or text message(s) or contact the school or other Advertiser directly. 

Please note, you cannot opt out of our sharing of your personal information with our Processors or Business Partners, or our sharing of deidentified information, or your personal information as required by law or legitimate business interests, as described in Sections III. B., D., and E. above. With respect to information captured and shared through cookies, pixel tags and other tracking technologies, and your ability to limit the sharing of your information through those channels, please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://www.niche.com/about/cookie-policy/) for your options. Also, if you opt out of receiving marketing-related emails from us, we may still send you important administrative messages, from which you cannot opt out.   

**_A special note about your telephone number_** – By providing your telephone number to us, you agree that this action constitutes an “inquiry” for purposes of telemarketing laws. Regardless of the fact that your telephone and/or mobile number may be listed with the Federal Do-Not-Call Registry or your State Do-Not-Call list, **_you are providing your express written consent to receive future information (including telemarketing) about products and services from us, and you hereby agree and consent to our contacting you using the information you have provided and will provide to us. This means we may contact you by e-mail, phone and/or mobile number (including use of automated dialing equipment and/or pre-recorded calls), text (SMS) message, social networks or any other means of communication that your wireless or other telecommunications device may be capable of receiving (e.g., video, etc.). You are not required to agree to this consent in order to obtain Services through us. This consent may be revoked by you at any time **_by removing your telephone number from your profile. For guidance in removing your telephone number, please see the help center article, available_** [**_here_**](https://niche.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/8120421644308-How-Do-I-Remove-My-Phone-Number-From-My-Profile) **_or on the Niche website,_** email us at support@niche.com and put the words “remove my telephone number” in the subject line of your email, or call us at 1-(844)-452-7758._** Please refer to the Niche [User Agreement](https://www.niche.com/about/terms/) for additional information regarding telephone consent.

**_Special rule for users under 16 years of age_** – So long as we have actual knowledge that you are under the age of 16 and reside in a state that requires us to do so, we will not sell your personally identifiable information to our Advertisers unless you “opt in” by requesting us to do so. You can opt in to information sharing with Advertisers by requesting that we share your information with schools or related entities for which you have expressed an interest or with parties that you wish to be considered for a scholarship. We may ask you or the person acting on your behalf (e.g., a parent or legal guardian) to verify your identity. Likewise, any public information that you post on the Site, including user reviews or opinion surveys, are considered public and you will be considered to have opted in to the sharing of such public information.  You may also “opt in” to having your personally identifiable information shared with our Advertisers by changing your communication settings in your profile. If you need help to do this, you may contact us at support@niche.com and tell us that you wish to opt in.

**V.** **Cross-border transfers of information** 

Our Site and the Services we offer through it are U.S. based and are controlled, operated and administered by Niche and its Processors from offices and servers within the United States. Our Site and this Privacy Policy is strictly intended for audiences located in the United States and are provided in accordance with and subject to applicable United States law. If you decide to continue to access our Site from your location outside the United States, you hereby agree that your use of the Site or any Services we may offer are subject to this Policy and your personal information will be transferred or processed in the United States, and you may have fewer privacy rights and protections than you have in your country of origin.

**VI.** **How long we keep your personal information, your right to delete and correct it** 

We retain your personal information as reasonably necessary to fulfill the purposes for which we collected it and you provided it, and to comply with our legal obligations. In no event will we keep your personal information for longer than is reasonably necessary for the purposes defined in this Policy. You also have the right to request that we delete your personal information, subject to certain exceptions, such as our need to prevent and protect against fraud or other illegal activity, to complete business transactions with you, and for such other purposes as allowed by law. You can correct or update your personal information by updating your profile. We are unable to make updates to your profile, but you have the option to make updates by logging into your profile and going into your settings. Our [How Do I Edit My Account](https://niche.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/8955759294484-How-Do-I-Edit-My-Account) article in the Niche Help Center will walk you through the process of editing your data. For more information on where and how long your personal information is stored, your requests to delete it or correct it, please contact us at the address set forth below in Section IX.

**VII.** **Security of your information** 

To help protect the privacy of your Personal Data collected by us, we maintain reasonable physical, technical and administrative safeguards. We update and test our security technology on an ongoing basis. We restrict access to your personal information to those employees who need to know that information in order to provide Services to you. In addition, we train our employees about the importance of confidentiality and maintaining the privacy and security of your information.

**VIII.** **Limitation of liability**

YOU UNDERSTAND AND AGREE THAT ANY DISPUTE OVER THE PRIVACY OF YOUR INFORMATION IS SUBJECT TO THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND THE NICHE USER AGREEMENT (INCLUDING ANY INDEMNIFICATION AND LIMITATIONS ON DAMAGES CONTAINED IN THAT AGREEMENT).

**IX.** **Questions, concerns or complaints – Contact Details**

If you have questions about our privacy practices and this Privacy Policy, or if you wish to correct any of your information or exercise your rights under the law or this Policy, you can contact us as follows: 

Niche.com, Inc.  
2840 Liberty Avenue  
Suite 202  
Pittsburgh, PA. 15222  
Email: support@niche.com  
Toll Free – (844)-452-7758

Please be specific when telling us what your request is.

**X.** **A note about Children**

Children under the age of 13 are not permitted to use the Niche Site or Services and we do not intentionally collect or maintain personal information from those who are under 13 years old. Protecting the privacy of children is very important to us. Thus, if we obtain actual knowledge that a user is under 13, we will take steps to remove that user’s personal information from our databases. We recommend that children between the ages of 13 and 18 obtain their parent’s permission before submitting information over the Internet. By using the Niche Site or Services, you are representing that you are at least 18 years old, or that you are at least 13 years old and have your parents’ permission to use the website and any Services offered by us.

**XI.** **NOTICE TO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS – YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

**If you are a California resident (“you” or a “California Customer”), California law may apply to how we collect and use your personal information, and what rights you have in some circumstances. The following terms supplement our Privacy Policy and explain the rights of California Customers under the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”).**

The following sets forth the categories of information we collect and purposes for which we may use a California Consumers’ personal information collected by us:

**_Categories of Personal Information We Collect About You:_**

The categories of personal information we may have collected about you or your use of our Services are:

* Identifiers, such as your name, alias, postal address, phone number, email address, log-in information, or unique personal identifiers (such as device ID, cookies, and IP address);
* Commercial information (such as Site engagement data);
* Protected classification characteristics;
* Internet or other network or device activity (such as browsing or search history or app usage, and advertisement interactions);
* Geo-location information relating to your computer or device when you interact with the Site;
* Professional or employment related information that you supply;
* Education information that you supply;
* Profile data about you and any inferences drawn from the profile data (such as characteristics, behaviors, attitudes);
* Information that identifies or can be reasonably associated with you.

In the past 12 months we have sold the information listed in the above categories to our Advertisers. We do not sell the personal information of California Customers that we know are minors under 16 years of age without affirmative authorization as required under the CCPA.  Additionally, during this time period we have also disclosed all or substantially all of this personal information to our Processors and Business Partners for permissible business reasons. More details on the personal information we may collect are set forth in the “Categories of Information We Collect and Process” section above, found [here](#section1). More details on the personal information we have sold or disclosed are set forth in the “With Whom We Share Your Information” section above, found [here](#section1). 

**_Metrics On Your Rights_**

Transparency is important to us, especially when it comes to helping you understand and exercise your rights under the CCPA. We’ve published some key metrics below showing how often our users engage with us to request their CCPA rights:

**Access Requests:** **Right to Know**

Received: 265  
Complied with: 55  
Denied: 210  
Average response time: 10 days

**Access Requests:** **Categories**

Received: 20  
Complied with: 6  
Denied: 14  
Average response time: 21 days

**Right to Delete**

Received: 4222  
Complied with: 577  
Denied: 3645  
Average response time: 16 days

**Right to Opt-out of Sale**

Received: 2796  
Complied with: 1119  
Denied: 1677  
Average response time: 6 days

The metrics above are for the period from December 1, 2022 through November 30, 2023, and represent interactions where users have contacted Niche and explicitly requested to exercise their CCPA rights. We’ll update these numbers from time to time to ensure we are providing you the most up-to-date information.

**_Categories of Sources from Which We Collected Personal Information_**

The sources from which we may have collected personal information about you or your use of the Services are:

* Directly from you;
* From other sources (such as from third parties and/or business partners);
* Through your use of the Services; and
* Publicly available records.

and as described in more detail in the Information We Collect and Obtain [here](#section1).

**_Your California Privacy Rights_**

A California Customer may request information about whether we have sold or disclosed personal information to any third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes or for our business purposes. In general, if we have made such a sale or disclosure of your personal information, upon receipt of a verified request from you, we are required to provide a list of all third parties to whom your personal information was either sold or disclosed for business purposes in the preceding 12 months following your request, as well as a list of the categories of personal information that were sold or disclosed, the sources of it, and what it was used for. You may also request a copy of the personal information that we have collected about you in the last 12 months. 

You may have certain additional rights under the CCPA. You may request that we delete certain information we have about you. There may be exemptions from such requests under applicable law. For example, we need certain types of information so that we can provide the Services to you and for compliance with applicable law. You may also have the right to receive information about the financial incentives that we offer to you (if any). You also have the right to not be discriminated against (as provided for in applicable law) for exercising certain of your rights under the CCPA. This means that we will not penalize you for exercising your rights by taking actions such as denying you Services; decreasing Service quality; or suggesting that we may penalize you for exercising your rights. Except as provided in Section III, above, we do not share your personal information collected by us with third parties for their direct marketing purposes without giving you the opportunity to opt out as more fully described above in Section IV. 

If you are a California resident, you may request information about our compliance with California law by calling us toll free at (844)-452-7758, emailing us at _support@niche.com_, or by writing to us at 2840 Liberty Avenue, Suite 202, Pittsburgh, PA, 15222 c/o “CA Privacy”, addressed to “Attention: California Privacy Matters.”  Any such request must include “California Privacy Rights Request” in the subject line and include your name, street address, city, state and ZIP code.  Please note that we are only required to respond to up to two requests per visitor each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this designated email address, mailing address or toll-free number.

**_Identity Verification and Additional Information to Needed to Process a Request_****.**  We reserve the right to confirm your California residence to process your requests and will need to confirm your identity to process your requests to exercise your information, access or deletion rights.  As part of this process, government identification may be required.   California Customers can empower an “authorized agent” to submit requests on their behalf.  We will require the authorized agent to have a written authorization recognized by law confirming that authority.  We cannot process your request if you do not provide us with sufficient detail to allow us to understand and respond to it or to verify your or your agent’s identity.

**_Do Not Track Disclosure_**.  California Business & Professions Code Section 22575(b) provides that California residents are entitled to know how Niche responds to “Do Not Track” browser settings. We currently do not respond to “Do Not Track” signals because a uniform technological standard has not yet been developed.

**XII.** **Nevada Privacy Rights**

**FOR RESIDENTS OF NEVADA ONLY**. In accordance with SB 220, Nevada consumers may opt-out of the sale of their personal information to third parties, as provided by law. If you reside in Nevada and you have provided us with your personal information, you may choose to opt-out of the sale of such personal information via the Datagrail privacy request form, accessible [here](https://www.niche.com/about/ccpa-request/). If you need help to opt out using the Datagrail privacy request form, then you can email us at _support@niche.com,_ with “Nevada Privacy Right” in the subject line, or call us toll free at (844)-452-7758 and we will guide you through the process. We may request additional information from you in order to verify your identity and/or the authenticity of your request. For purposes of this opt-out, a “sale” of your personal information means an exchange of it by us to another party for money and the other party buys it from us for re-sale to a third party. 

**XIII.** **Changes to this Privacy Policy and Effective Date**

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time and for any reason, including our business reasons or in order to comply with changing privacy laws. Unless otherwise provided by applicable law, any changes that we make to this Policy will be published on our Site and will become effective upon publication. Your continued use of the Services or the Site will constitute your acceptance of any such changes to the fullest extent permitted by law. You are encouraged to review this Policy from time to time, to make sure you are current with our privacy practices.

**_The Effective Date of this Privacy Policy is: June 30, 2020_**

Discover the schools, companies, and neighborhoods that are right for you.

Do you work for a school or college? [Claim Your School](https://www.niche.com/claim-your-school/)

©2024 Niche.com Inc.
